Inventory of the Božidar Puric Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Printed Matter, 1943-1969 (Box 14-15)
  - "Les Témoignages qui ne seront pas cités au procès du général Dragoljub Mihailovićh à Belgrade,", 1946 (Folder 15: 12)
  - "Tito's Yugoslavia," The Dublin Review reprint, April 1946 (Folder 15: 13)
  - Vidovdan, September-November 1964, May-June 1965 (Folder 15: 14)
  - Yugoslav Information Sheet, July 1946 (Folder 15: 15)
  - "The Yugoslav National Democratic Union," Yugoslav Document No. 1, undated (Folder 15: 16)
  - "Yugoslavia at War," Yugoslav Documents no.2, London, 1942 (Folder 15: 17)
  - Clippings, 1943-1968 and undated (Folder 15: 18-21)
- Photographs, 1915-1973 and undated (Box 15)
  Prints document official and social life, as well as family members.
  Arranged by subject, then chronologically
  - Official gatherings, 1936, 1948 and undated (Folder 15)
    - Monument inauguration, 1936 (16 prints) (Folder 15: 22)
    - Office scene, Paris, 1948 (1 print) (Folder 15: 22)
    - Unidentified government officials with Puric, undated (19 prints) (Folder 15: 22)
    - Dinner party, undated (3 prints) (Folder 15: 22)
    - Nikola Pasic, undated (10 prints) (Folder 15: 22)
    - Military parade, Paris, undated (6 prints) (Folder 15: 22)
  - Social gatherings, 1915-1973 and undated (Folder 15: 23)
    - Božidar Puriè, Ontario, Canada, undated (1 print) (Folder 15: 23)
    - Božidar Puriè with friends, 1915, 1917 and undated (20 prints) (Folder 15: 23)
    - Various individuals with clergy, undated (13 prints) (Folder 15: 23)
    - Restaurant scene, circa 1927 (2 prints) (Folder 15: 23)
    - Unidentified, 1938, 1973, and undated (3 prints) (Folder 15: 23)
  - Children and family members, 1937 and undated (Folder 15: 24)
  - Petar II, King of Yugoslavia, 1938, 1972 and undated (Folder 15: 25)
    - Petar II, King of Yugoslavia, undated (2 prints) (Folder 15: 25)
    - King and Queen of Yugoslavia, undated (5 prints) (Folder 15: 25)
  - Royal visit, Prince Pavle, Bohinj, Slovenia, undated (Folder 15: 26)
  - Unidentified, 1938, 1973, and undated (17 prints) (Folder 15: 27)
- Oversize materials, 1912-1963 and undated (Box 16-25)
  Contains photograph albums, certificates, writings, poster, and map.
  - Photograph albums, 1912-1935 (Folder 16-24)
    - "Balkanski Rat,", 1912-1913 (Folder 16-22)
      - 1912-1913, I (Folder 16)
      - 1912-1913, III (Folder 17)
      - 1912-1913, IV (Folder 18)
      - 1912-1913, V (Folder 19)
      - 1912-1913, VI (Folder 20)
      - 1912-1913, VII (Folder 21)
      - 1912-1913, VIII (Folder 22)
    - Božidar Puric attending various official events, circa 1930 (Folder 23)
    - Božidar Puric's social and official gatherings, circa 1930 (Folder 24)
    - Government funeral procession, circa 1930 (Folder 24)
    - "Conférence du Conseil Permanent de l'Entente Balkanique, Bucarest, 9-12 Mai 1935," (Folder 24)
  - "Italy and the Balkans," map, The Edinburgh Geographical Institute, 1938 (Folder 25)
  - Photographs, 1930-1950, and undated (Folder 25)
    - Group of individuals associated with Božidar Puric, 1930s (Folder 25)
    - Glasgow, 1930s (Folder 25)
    - Episcopal portrait, Chicago, 1963 (Folder 25)
    - Božidar Puric portraits, undated (6 prints) (Folder 25)
    - Božidar Puric with a child, undated (Folder 25)
  - Certificate and writings, 1901 and undated (Folder 25)
    - Birth certificate church record, 1907 (Folder 25)
    - "Prica o Nama," reprinted poem by Božidar Puric, undated (Folder 25)
    - "Rade Jovanovic-Musa," writings, undated (Folder 25)
  - Decree of appointment, 1918 (Folder Oversize folder: Map case)
  - Conference in Chicago photograph, late 1950s (Folder Oversize folder: Map case)
  - Portrait, pencil drawings, Paris, 1937 (Folder Oversize folder: Map case)
  - "Hommage aux héros yougoslaves et français unis dans la mort et dans la Victoire le 15 Septembre 1918," commemorative cloth printed in commemoration of the twentieth anniversary of the event, 1938 (Folder Oversize folder: Map case)
  - H.R.H. Princess Elizabeth portrait clipping, Sunday Dispatch, 6 January 1952 (Folder Oversize folder: Map case)
  - "Médailles commémoratives de Serbie et d'Orient," poster, undated (Folder Oversize folder: Map case)